<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Uncategorized on Dr Random</title><link>http://drrandom.org/tags/Uncategorized/</link><description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Dr Random</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 14:40:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://drrandom.org/tags/Uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moved Comments to Disqus</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2012/04/20/moved-comments-to-disqus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2012/04/20/moved-comments-to-disqus/</guid><description>As of yesterday the comments on the blog here are now officially hosted by Disqus. If anyone has tried leaving comments in the past only to have them never show up (or disappear at some point), I apologize for that. The spam was a little crazy&amp;hellip;.and by a little crazy I mean effing insane, It got to the point where I was unable to separate the wheat from the chaff, and went through a couple different strategies to try and get things under control&amp;hellip;Disqus is the latest (and hopefully last) of these strategies.</description></item><item><title>Lot’s of Changes</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2009/09/09/lots-of-changes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 20:47:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2009/09/09/lots-of-changes/</guid><description>As of today I have updated several things on the site. First, I have a new hosting provider, WinHost . This was primarily a financial decision (saving $3.03 a month, not a lot but hey, every little bit helps, right?), but it looks like there are some nice technical advantages to switching as well. Some of these are things like IIS 7 hosting, and SQL Server access. Also you get unlimited domain name pointers, so the IThinkIn.</description></item><item><title>Typemock License Giveaway</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2009/05/20/typemock-license-giveaway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2009 16:46:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2009/05/20/typemock-license-giveaway/</guid><description>[Unit Testing ](1) ASP.NET? [ASP.NET unit testing ](2) has never been this easy. Typemock is launching a new product for ASP.NET developers – the ASP.NET Bundle – and for the launch will be giving out FREE licenses to bloggers and their readers.
The ASP.NET Bundle is the ultimate ASP.NET unit testing solution, and offers both Typemock Isolator , a unit test tool and Ivonna , the Isolator add-on for ASP.</description></item><item><title>Some (good?) string extension methods</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2009/02/22/some-good-string-extension-methods/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 17:19:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2009/02/22/some-good-string-extension-methods/</guid><description>So, to take a slightly different turn from my usual meta discussions of process, theory, and architecture, there have been several people who have offered up some examples of extension methods that they have found useful, now that .Net 3.5 is roaring along nicely. There are some collections of such utilities, like the Umbrella project , and some folks like Bill Wagner who have written books on the subject (okay, there are other things in there too), so I thought I might as well throw my hat into the ring as well.</description></item><item><title>New addiction: StackOverflow.com</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2008/10/16/new-addiction-stackoverflow-com/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2008 03:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2008/10/16/new-addiction-stackoverflow-com/</guid><description>Like so many others, I&amp;rsquo;ve been sucked into the alure of StackOverflow .
This is kinda like a porn addiction, only more destructive to personal relationships.</description></item><item><title>How important is your Code Audience?</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2008/04/08/how-important-is-your-code-audience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2008 17:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2008/04/08/how-important-is-your-code-audience/</guid><description>We had a friend visiting from out of town last night, and she is apparently fond of “Top Chef”. This was the first time I had encountered this particular “reality” based show, and I found in a lot of ways it was like the majority of the rest of the shows out there; trying hard to create drama where there really isn&amp;rsquo;t any. In this particular episode there was a challenge to cook food for a neighborhood block party.</description></item><item><title>I’m a Nerd</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/10/10/im-a-nerd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 23:06:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/10/10/im-a-nerd/</guid><description>I think this falls pretty solidly in the DUH! category.</description></item><item><title>I’m getting more fluent…and its kinda strange</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/09/15/im-getting-more-fluent-and-its-kinda-strange/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 15:29:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/09/15/im-getting-more-fluent-and-its-kinda-strange/</guid><description>About two weeks ago I crafted my first Fluent Interface. Since then I&amp;rsquo;m finding myself seeing more and more places where I think such an approach would be useful. The part that I&amp;rsquo;m finding odd is that it is something that just recently became a possibility for me. The big motivating factor behind that I believe was reading the post that Martin Fowler did on the subject, in which he basically describes it as a super-great idea (okay, I&amp;rsquo;m paraphrasing, but you get the idea).</description></item><item><title>My new favorite phrase</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/09/04/my-new-favorite-phrase/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 15:45:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/09/04/my-new-favorite-phrase/</guid><description>I found this little jewel in Martin Fowler&amp;rsquo;s recent post OneLanguage
&amp;hellip; a jigger of 80 proof ugliness &amp;hellip;
Check the post for the full context if you need to know what is a jigger of 80 proof ugliness, but this phrase, for whatever reason, gave me large amounts of joy just now.</description></item><item><title>Forcing redirection to HTTPS in ASP.Net</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/08/17/forcing-redirection-to-https-in-asp-net/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 21:02:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/08/17/forcing-redirection-to-https-in-asp-net/</guid><description>I ran into this issue today when trying to find a quick and dirty script to enforce redirection from HTTP to HTTPS for an intranet site we&amp;rsquo;re enabling for HTTPS (yes, I know SSL on an intranet??? One word – Audit). I thought this would be easy&amp;hellip;I half expected that there would be an IIS setting to handle this for me; I was wrong on both counts. So what I ended up doing is using an old DNN HttpModule which was set up to allow the user to specify specific tabs in DNN for SSL, and greatly simplifying things to work to my advantage.</description></item><item><title>Linux PVR – Part 2</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/06/10/linux-pvr-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2007 13:17:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/06/10/linux-pvr-part-2/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of poking around the MythTV and Knoppmyth sites recently trying to figure out what is going to work best in my current situation. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve got cable, and not satellite, it would seem that it is possible to get all of the non-encrypted content from my provider, as long as I have a capture card with QAM support. These cards seem to be HD cards overall (at least I haven&amp;rsquo;t found one that is supported that is not HD), which makes sense given the QAM signal will be a digital signal.</description></item><item><title>To TOOP or OOP? How to decide?</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/05/29/to-toop-or-oop-how-to-decide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 21:12:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/05/29/to-toop-or-oop-how-to-decide/</guid><description>Its been a while now, but Roy Osherove posted some articles about Testable Object-Oriented Programming. That is, designing your code to be testable by default. The part of this that is most interesting is that he suggests that sometimes you need to sacrifice encapsulation in favor of being able to test your code. This is where one of the biggest flaws with TDD (at least in my opinion) begins to show.</description></item><item><title>Genuine Advantage Notification – WTF?</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/04/04/genuine-advantage-notification-wtf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/04/04/genuine-advantage-notification-wtf/</guid><description>This morning I was greeted by a friendly message from Windows Update saying I had updates ready to install. Because I&amp;rsquo;m the curious sort who likes to see how many issues MS has to deal with regularly, I decided to use “Advanced” mode to see what the updates were (By “Advanced” of course it means anyone who is concerned about what is getting installed on their machines&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen I Robot, I know that one day the great machine can decide the only way to save us from our selves is to format our hard drives).</description></item><item><title>SQL Reporting Services Problems Finally Solved!</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/03/09/sql-reporting-services-problems-finally-solved/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 16:04:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/03/09/sql-reporting-services-problems-finally-solved/</guid><description>A little background: I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with a SQL 2000 Reporting Server for about 4 months now, trying to do some integration into an intranet app, and some reporting conversion. For the last 3 months or so, the web services API, and the ability to publish from within Visual Studio have been gone. Needless to say this has put a serious damper on my ability to integrate RS into the client&amp;rsquo;s intranet.</description></item><item><title>Linux PVR – Part 1 (Prolouge)</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/02/24/linux-pvr-part-1-prolouge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2007 20:23:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/02/24/linux-pvr-part-1-prolouge/</guid><description>My wife and I have decided to try and put together a PVR box to make life a little easier. With Lana getting old enough to pay attention to grown-up TV, and the fact that there are 4 shows we like to watch that happen at the same time, it seems appropriate (not to mention being able to record Sesame Street for the baby).
So here is what I’ve figured out so far:</description></item><item><title>More on Marker Interfaces</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/01/16/more-on-marker-interfaces/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 17:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/01/16/more-on-marker-interfaces/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the “Framework Design Guidelines: Conventions, Idioms, and Patterns for Reusable .NET Libraries” book recently, and I came across a section discussing interface design, which had direct bearing on one of my earlier posts regarding programmer intent. They basically state flat out that you should never use marker interfaces in .Net. Instead, you should favor custom attributes, and then test the type for that attribute. This was interesting to me, since I have been trying to determine what, if any, value marker interfaces would have in .</description></item><item><title>Multiple IEs</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/01/08/multiple-ies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2007 16:23:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/01/08/multiple-ies/</guid><description>I recently ran across an intranet reporting app which required IE6 (or, I should say, would not work with IE7 or FireFox 2). I upgraded to IE7 originally after numerous javascript errors, and a desire to check out CardSpace, and thus far had not had too many problems. This was a potential issue, however.
Fortunately there is a ready made solution: Multiple IE&amp;rsquo;s. This little gem is a single installer, which will allow you to install any version of IE from 3 through 6 in it&amp;rsquo;s own folder so it does not interfere with the default install.</description></item><item><title>I figured as much</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2007/01/02/i-figured-as-much/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2007 15:34:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2007/01/02/i-figured-as-much/</guid><description>Here are my results of the Superhero Personality Test&amp;hellip;Does it surprise anyone, really?
Your results:
You are Spider-Man
Spider-Man &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;80&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 80% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Green Lantern &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;65&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 65% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Iron Man &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;55&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 55% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Catwoman &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;55&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 55% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; The Flash &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;50&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 50% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Hulk &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;50&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 50% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Superman &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;45&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 45% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Supergirl &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;40&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 40% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Robin &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;35&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 35% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Batman &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;35&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 35% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Wonder Woman &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; noshade=&amp;quot;noshade&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;4&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;30&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; 30% &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/table&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; You are intelligent, witty, &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;a bit geeky and have great&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; power and responsibility.</description></item><item><title>WinFX By Any Other Name….</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2006/06/15/winfx-by-any-other-name/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2006 17:11:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2006/06/15/winfx-by-any-other-name/</guid><description>It looks like, to help avoid confusion, and questions from developers, Microsoft is renaming WinFx to the .Net Framework 3.0. Evedently people were under the impression that WinFX was a seperate entity.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the post:
http://blogs.msdn.com/somasegar/archive/2006/06/09/624300.aspx</description></item><item><title>Thread Exception Change in .Net 2.0</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2006/05/31/thread-exception-change-in-net-2-0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2006 15:47:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2006/05/31/thread-exception-change-in-net-2-0/</guid><description>I just learned that Microsoft changed the way unhandled exceptions in Threads are propogated in .Net 2.0 vs the way they worked in 1.1. With 2.0 any unhandled exceptions in a thread will not only cause that thread to exit, but will also be bubbled up to the thread that started the offending thread. Overall, I think this is a good thing, since not only will it force people to handle exceptions within their thread code, but it will also eliminate the problem of processes mysteriously stopping if there is an unhandled exception on a thread.</description></item><item><title>Learn something new every….</title><link>http://drrandom.org/2006/05/24/learn-something-new-every/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2006 16:30:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drrandom.org/2006/05/24/learn-something-new-every/</guid><description>It just goes to show that there are always little surprises waiting around the corner. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at least casually at .Net 2.0 since Beta 2, and I even read through the “What&amp;rsquo;s New” for C# 2.0 to see if I missed anything. Somehow I managed not to notice Implicit Delegate Assignment (or at least that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m calling it).
It is now possible to assign a delegate using just the Class and Method name&amp;hellip;you no longer have to create a new instance of the delegate type.</description></item></channel></rss>